* 

Privacy Policy
==============

1. [Home](https://www.schoolcare.co.uk/) 
3. Privacy Policy

### Website Privacy Policy – 25 May 2018

This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect from you when you use our website. In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and, by law, we are required to provide you with information about us, about why and how we use your data, and about the rights you have over your data.

### Who are we?

We are Professional Software Design LTD. Our address is Suite 5, Hillfields House, Castleman Way, Ringwood, Hampshire, BH24 3BA. You can contact us by post at the above address, by email at compliance@psdgroup.co.uk or by telephone on +44 (0)333 240 2626

We are not required to have a data protection officer, so any enquiries about our use of your personal data should be addressed to the contact details above.

### How we use your information

* When you use our website
* When you submit an enquiry via our website
* When you sign up to receive our newsletter
* When you download a sample document
* When you submit a review about us
* When you take part in our feedback survey
* Your rights as a data subject
* Your right to complain
* Updates to this privacy policy

### When you use our website

When you use our website to browse our products and services and view the information we make available, a number of cookies are used by us and by third parties to allow the website to function, to collect useful information about visitors and to help to make your user experience better.

Some of the cookies we use are strictly necessary for our website to function, and we don’t ask for your consent to place these on your computer. These cookies are shown below.

However, for those cookies that are useful but not strictly necessary we will always ask for your consent before placing them.

As well as the cookies we use, various third parties also place them on your computer, again with your consent.

| Cookie | Type | Duration | Description |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| 3rdparty | Third Party | During Chatting Session | Checks for 3rd party domain cookies and checks if they are supported |
| autoinvite\_callback | Session | During Chatting Session | This cookie is used for proper handling JS Api and callback on\_message |
| chat\_running | Third Party | 24h Hide | Used to check if chat is pending |
| lc..secret\_id | Third Party | During Chatting Session | It is used by communication protocol |
| lc\_invitation\_opened | Third Party | During Chatting Session | Keeps state of the LiveChat greeting |
| lc\_sso9762288 | Third Party | Expires in 32 Months | LiveChat will need these in the future for technical changes |
| lc\_sso | Third Party | Expires in 3 Years | It is used by communication protocol |
| lc\_window\_state | Session | During Chatting Session | It tells if window is minimised or not |
| main\_window\_timestamp, main\_window\_timestamp\_0 | Third Party | During Chatting Session | Used to track app state between different tabs |
| message\_text | Third Party | During Chatting Session | Contains text typed by visitor before message is sent |
| notification\[personal\_invitation\] | Third Party | During Chatting Session | Is the cookie for remembering that there was a greeting sent to the customer |
| Notification\[status ping\] | Third Party | During Chatting Session | Timestamp of the last ping, information about agent availability and state of the visitor |
| recent\_window | Third Party | During Chatting Session | Used to track app state between different tabs |
| secret\_token\_ | Third Party | 24h | It is used by communication protocol |
| viewed\_cookie\_policy | Persistent | 1 Year | Used to remember whether a visitor has accepted the cookie policy on the site. |
| \_eye\_catcher | Third Party | During Chatting Session | It is connected to LiveChat eye catcher |
| \_ga | Persistent | 2 Years | Used to track of the number of times a visitor has been to the site pertaining to the cookie, when their first visit was and when their last visit occurred. Google Analytics uses the information from this cookie to calculate things like Days and Visits. |
| \_gat | Session | 10 Minutes | Used to manage the rate at which page view requests are made |
| \_gid | Session | 10 Minutes | Used to distinguish users |
| \_lc.visitor\_id. | Third Party | Expires in 32 Months | id of the visitor |
| \_lc\_vv | Third Party | During Chatting Session | LiveChat version |
| \_livechat | Third Party | Expires in 3 Years | Responsible for many things required for LiveChat to work properly, for example - last operator |
| \_livechat\_chat | Third Party | Expires in 32 Months | id of the ongoing chat |
| \_livechat\_lastvisit | Third Party | Expires in 3 Years | Timestamp of last |

For more information about our use of cookies, please see our cookie policy.

### When you submit an enquiry via our website

When you submit an enquiry via our website, we ask you for your name, contact telephone number and email address.

We use this information to respond to your query, including providing you with any requested information about our products and services. We may also email you several times after your enquiry in order to follow up on your interest and ensure that we have answered your it to your satisfaction. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in providing accurate information prior to a sale.

Your enquiry is stored and processed as an email which is hosted by Professional Software Design Limited in the UK. It is also logged on a CRM system on a cloud server based in UK, a country which the EU says has adequate data protection laws in place to protect your data.

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

We keep enquiry emails for two years, after which they are securely archived and kept for seven years, when we delete them. CRM records are kept for three years after the last contact with you.

### When you sign up to receive our newsletter

When you sign up to receive our newsletter, we ask for your name and your email address.

We will ask for your consent to use your name and email address to email you our newsletter which contains information about our products and other information which we feel might be of interest to you.

You can withdraw your consent at any time and we will stop sending you the newsletter.

Your name and email address are shared with a third party mailing system which is based in Paris, France. This company has contractually committed to providing appropriate safeguards for your personal data which means it will be protected in line with the legal requirements of the European Union.

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

We keep your personal data for as long as we produce and distribute our newsletter. If you withdraw your consent, we will mark your details so that they are not used and delete them after two years.

### When you download a sample document

When you request to download a sample document, such as a white paper, we ask for your name, company name (which is optional) and your email address.

We use this information to email you a link to download the requested document. We may also email you after your download in order to follow up on your interest in our products and services. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in marketing to prospects for our products and services.

Your name and email address are shared with a third party mailing system which is based in Paris, France. This company has contractually committed to providing appropriate safeguards for your personal data which means it will be protected in line with the legal requirements of the European Union.

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

Your personal data is stored for one year after you requested your download, after which it is deleted.

### When you submit a review about us

When you submit a review about us we record your name, your email address and your IP (Internet Protocol) address, which is the address of your computer on the Internet.

We use this information to provide verified independent views about our products and services to potential customers. Your name and the content of your review (but not your email address or IP address) may be publicly displayed on our website. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in marketing our products and services.

Your details are shared with a third party reviews system which is based within the European Economic Area (EEA).

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

Your personal data is stored for as long as we are marketing the product or services that the review refers to, after which it is deleted. You may ask us to remove your review at any time.

### When you take part in our feedback survey

When you take part in our feedback survey, we record your name, your email address, your organisation name, your job role and your answers to questions we ask about your opinion of, and use of, our products and services.

We use this information to develop and improve our products and services and our customer relationships. Your job role, organisation and some or all of your comments may be publicly displayed on our website as a testimonial. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in marketing our products and services.

Your details are shared with a third party surveys system which is based within the European Economic Area (EEA).  
We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

Your personal data is stored for two years, or for as long as we are marketing the product or services that the review refers to, whichever is shorter. You may ask us to remove a testimonial that is based on your feedback from our website at any time.

### Your rights as a data subject

By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate. If we have asked for your consent to process your personal data, you may withdraw that consent at any time.

If we are processing your personal data for reasons of consent or to fulfil a contract, you can ask us to give you a copy of the information in a machine-readable format so that you can transfer it to another provider.

If we are processing your personal data for reasons of consent or legitimate interest, you can request that your data be erased.

You have the right to ask us to stop using your information for a period of time if you believe we are not doing so lawfully.

Finally, in some circumstances you can ask us not to reach decisions affecting you using automated processing or profiling.  
To submit a request regarding your personal data by email, post or telephone, please use the contact information provided above in the Who Are We section of this policy.

### Your right to complain

If you have a complaint about our use of your information, we would prefer you to contact us directly in the first instance so that we can address your complaint. However, you can also contact the Information Commissioner’s Office via their website at www.ico.org.uk/concerns or write to them at:

Information Commissioner’s Office  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF

### Updates to this privacy policy

We regularly review and, if appropriate, update this privacy policy from time to time, and as our services and use of personal data evolves. If we want to make use of your personal data in a way that we haven’t previously identified, we will contact you to provide information about this and, if necessary, to ask for your consent.

### SchoolCare Offices

* Suite 5a, Hillfields House, Castleman Way, Ringwood, Hampshire, BH24 3BA
* 0333 3581333

### Latest Posts

* [Transforming Education with Cloud-Based Asset Management Platforms](https://www.schoolcare.co.uk/transforming-education-with-cloud-based-asset-management-platforms/)
    
    26 Feb 2024

    19 Feb 2024

### [](http://feeds.bbci.co.uk/news/education/rss.xml) [Latest Tweets](https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/education)

### Sign Up to Our Newsletters Today!

Copyright © 2024 SchoolCare - All trademarks acknowledged

The SchoolCare website uses cookies. By continuing to browse the site you are agreeing to our use of cookies. Accept For more details about cookies and how to manage them [Read More](https://www.schoolcare.co.uk/privacy-policy)

Privacy & Cookies Policy

Close

#### Privacy Overview

This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may have an effect on your browsing experience.

Necessary

 Necessary

Always Enabled

Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.

Non-necessary

 Non-necessary

Any cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.

SAVE & ACCEPT
